Guide to the Cecile Pineda Papers, 1959 - 1998
Department of Special Collections
Cecile Pineda Papers,
1959 - 1998
Special Collections M1176
Pineda, Cecile.
29 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Selected portions of various journals are restricted for 72 years from date of creation of the journal. Photocopies with the selected sections deleted have been placed in the collection for researcher use.
Provenance
Purchased, 2000.
Biography
San Francisco Bay Area writer, who founded and directed the troupe, Theater of Man, 1969-1981. In 1985 she made her novelist debut with the publication of FACE, and the following year saw the publication of FRIEZE. Her creative work has received the National Endowment Fiction Fellowship and her 1992 novel, THE LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON, was named notable book of the year by the New York Times.
Scope and Content
35 holograph journals from 1959 to the present, tape and video recordings of the author's work, drafts of unpublished work, photographs, literary and professional correspondence, teaching files, publishing files, and personal files.
Series Description and Container Listing
- Series 1. Theatre of Man files
  - Subseries 1. Acting/Directing materials, Workshop exercises & materials
    - Animal exercises - instructions, Creator's Id No. .01 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Audition materials, Creator's Id No. .02 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Auschwitz phrases, Creator's Id No. .03 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Capricio images, Creator's Id No. .04 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Coda: argument phrases, Creator's Id No. .05 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cellular images, Creator's Id No. .06 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Directing: timing / developmental exercises, Creator's Id No. .07 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Eight-line Shakespeare scenes, Creator's Id No. .08 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Exercises: vocal / physical / acting [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. .09 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Exercises: vocal / physical / acting [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. .09 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Improvisation: Outsider art, Creator's Id No. .1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Labyrinth exercise: trial phrases, Creator's Id No. .11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Motivation exercises, Creator's Id No. .12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Munch images, Creator's Id No. .13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Myths / stories, Creator's Id No. .14 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Phrases: group collage (coda), Creator's Id No. .15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Piranesi images, Creator's Id No. .16 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Presence exercise: Haiku, Creator's Id No. .17 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Rituals: preparation, Creator's Id No. .18 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Ritual: verb, Creator's Id No. .19 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Surrealism images, Creator's Id No. .2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - School notes: Pinter / Ibsen, Creator's Id No. .21 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - School notes: MFA exam [1 of 3], Creator's Id No. .22 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - School notes: MFA exam [2 of 3], Creator's Id No. .22 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - School notes: MFA exam [3 of 3], Creator's Id No. .22 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sound and movement exercises, Creator's Id No. .23 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Sound and movement: two character scenes, Creator's Id No. .24 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Texturing: two-line scenes: two & three characters, Creator's Id No. .25 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Two character scenes, Creator's Id No. .26 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Two-line scenes with movement archetypes, Creator's Id No. .27 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Workshop exercises, Creator's Id No. .28 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Workshop: Lone Mountain Experimental Theater1974 Jan., Creator's Id No. .29 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Workshop: origins, Creator's Id No. .3 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Workshop: pre-Serpent, Nov. 1974; Cal, 1971 Spring, Creator's Id No. .31 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Workshop: Firehouse1971 - 1972, Creator's Id No. .32 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Workshop: special scheduled, Creator's Id No. .33 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Workshop1972 Spring, Creator's Id No. .34 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 2. Correspondence, publicity, press
    - Argumenta Festival, Creator's Id No. 1.01 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Children's Shows, Creator's Id No. 1.02 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Colleagues / Friends, Creator's Id No. 1.03 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - After Eurydice1972 - 1973, Creator's Id No. 1.04 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Fabric artists, Creator's Id No. 1.05 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Fando & Lis1976, Creator's Id No. 1.06 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence [1 of 3], Creator's Id No. 1.07 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence [2 of 3], Creator's Id No. 1.07 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence [3 of 3], Creator's Id No. 1.07 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Murder in the Cathedral1969 - 1970, Creator's Id No. 1.08 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Nancy Festival, Creator's Id No. 1.09 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Neighborhood Arts Programs, Creator's Id No. 1.1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Playwrights [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 1.11 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Playwrights [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 1.11 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - ProVisional Theater, Creator's Id No. 1.12 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Serpent1971, Creator's Id No. 1.13 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Stoneground1974, Creator's Id No. 1.14 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - The Trial1975 - 1976, Creator's Id No. 1.15 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Office of Advanced Drama Research, Creator's Id No. 1.16 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Organizational history, Creator's Id No. 1.17 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Personnel [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 1.18 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Personnel [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 1.18 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Poland1977, Creator's Id No. 1.19 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Presentations, Creator's Id No. 1.2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Press (reviews) [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 1.21 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Press (reviews) [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 1.21 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Press releases [1 of 3], Creator's Id No. 1.22 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Press releases [2 of 3], Creator's Id No. 1.22 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Press releases [3 of 3], Creator's Id No. 1.22 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Publicity [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 1.23 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Publicity [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 1.23 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Recommendations, Creator's Id No. 1.24 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Subleasers, Creator's Id No. 1.25 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Theatre Vicinal, Creator's Id No. 1.26 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3. Performance texts, Developmental texts, photographs
    - After Eurydice performance text, Creator's Id No. 2.01 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - After Eurydice rehearsal photographs1972, Creator's Id No. 2.02 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - After Eurydice performance photographs1973, Creator's Id No. 2.03 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Bear's Bash photographs, Golden Gate Park, 1973, Creator's Id No. 2.04 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Blake's JOB, 11970, Creator's Id No. 2.05 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Blake's JOB, 21970, Creator's Id No. 2.06 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Blake's JOB, 31970, Creator's Id No. 2.07 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Blake's JOB, 41970, Creator's Id No. 2.08 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Fando & Lis: Arrabal1976, Creator's Id No. 2.09 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Fool of the World photographs1972, Creator's Id No. 2.1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fool of the World text1972, Creator's Id No. 2.11 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Goya photographs1979, Creator's Id No. 2.12 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Medea photographs1976, Creator's Id No. 2.13 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Medea text1976, Creator's Id No. 2.14 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Medea: preliminary drafts [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 2.15 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Medea: preliminary drafts [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 2.15 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Medea research [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 2.16 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Medea research [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 2.16 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mimesis photos, Creator's Id No. 2.17 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Murder in the Cathedral photographs, Creator's Id No. 2.18 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Murder in the Cathedral text1969 - 1970, Creator's Id No. 2.19 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Performanc Space photographs1975 - 1981, Creator's Id No. 2.2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Rainbow Caper photographs1974, Creator's Id No. 2.21 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Serpent photographs1971, Creator's Id No. 2.22 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Stoneground music / notes1974, Creator's Id No. 2.23 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Stoneground photographs, Creator's Id No. 2.24 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Stoneground research & illustrations, Creator's Id No. 2.25 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Stoneground text original [1 of 2]1974, Creator's Id No. 2.26 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Stoneground text original [2 of 2]1974, Creator's Id No. 2.26 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Stoneground textual revisions [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 2.27 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Stoneground textual revisions [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 2.27 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Stoneground textual development, Creator's Id No. 2.28 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Threesomes text1977, Creator's Id No. 2.29 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Threesomes textual development, Creator's Id No. 2.3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Threesomes early draft, Creator's Id No. 2.31 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Threesomes photographs, Creator's Id No. 2.32 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Time / Piece photographs1978, Creator's Id No. 2.33 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Trial photographs, Creator's Id No. 2.34 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Trial research, Creator's Id No. 2.35 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - The Trial text1975, Creator's Id No. 2.36 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Trial text early draft, Creator's Id No. 2.37 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - The Trial: staging schema, Creator's Id No. 2.38 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 4. Rehearsal logs & notes
    - After Eurydice developmental rehearsal log, 1972, Creator's Id No. 3.01 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - After Eurydice rehearsal log, 1973, Creator's Id No. 3.02 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Company records: rosters, rehearsal schedules [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 3.03 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Company records: rosters, rehearsal schedules [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 3.03 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Goya rehearsal log & notes [1 of 3]1979, Creator's Id No. 3.04 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Goya rehearsal log & notes [2 of 3]1979, Creator's Id No. 3.04 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Goya rehearsal log & notes [3 of 3]1979, Creator's Id No. 3.04 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Medea rehearsals / chorus assignments1976, Creator's Id No. 3.05 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Murder rehearsal notes1969 - 1970, Creator's Id No. 3.06 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Murder rehearsal log, Creator's Id No. 3.07 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Murder: notes & research, Creator's Id No. 3.08 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Murder model book, Creator's Id No. 3.09 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Music, Creator's Id No. 3.1 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Serpent rehearsal log1971, Creator's Id No. 3.11 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Serpent rehearsal notes, Creator's Id No. 3.12 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Stoneground rehearsal log [1 of 3]1974, Creator's Id No. 3.13 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Stoneground rehearsal log [2 of 3]1974, Creator's Id No. 3.13 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Stoneground rehearsal log [3 of 3]1974, Creator's Id No. 3.13 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Threesome rehearsal log, performance notes1977, Creator's Id No. 3.14 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Time / Piece rehearsal log, 1978, Creator's Id No. 3.15 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Trial company records, Creator's Id No. 3.16 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Trial rehearsal logs: two line labyrinth phrases [1 of 2]1975, Creator's Id No. 3.17 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Trial rehearsal logs: two line labyrinth phrases [2 of 2]1975, Creator's Id No. 3.17 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - After Eurydice rehearsal log and notes [1 of 6]1972 - 1973 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - After Eurydice rehearsal log and notes [2 of 6]1972 - 1973 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - After Eurydice rehearsal log and notes [3 of 6]1972 - 1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Fool of the World: rehearsal log and notes, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Fool of the World: script, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Fool of the World: script, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Fool of the World: script, complete / back in complete1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Fool of the World: script, only revised copy but text text as performed1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Fool of the World: stage manager's book, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Fool of the World: typescript, 1st draft1972 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Untitled: typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - After Eurydice: director's notebook, 1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - After Eurydice: notes, material1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - After Eurydice: notes, material1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - After Eurydice: performance text, 1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - After Eurydice rehearsal log and notes [4 of 6]1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - After Eurydice rehearsal log and notes [5 of 6]1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - After Eurydice rehearsal log and notes [6 of 6]1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - After Eurydice: rehearsal notes [1 of 3],1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - After Eurydice: rehearsal notes [2 of 3],1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - After Eurydice: rehearsal notes [3 of 3],1972 - 1973 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Bear's Bash rehearsal log and notes1973 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Bear's Bash rehearsal log and notes1973 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Producing Bear's Bash (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Production: Rainbow Caper (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Production: Rainbow Caper (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Rainbow Caper: notes 1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Rainbow Caper rehearsal log and notes [1 of 2]1974 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Rainbow Caper rehearsal log and notes [2 of 2]1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Rainbow Caper: script, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Rainbow Caper: script suggestions1974 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Resumes, etc., 1974 Summer (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Stoneground: 12 - choreography1974 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Stoneground: 16 - choreography1974 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Stoneground: Bomarzo index1974 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Stoneground: Bomarzo notes, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Stoneground: Bomarzo opera libretto, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Stoneground: Bomarzo scenario1974 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Stoneground: Etruscan images1974 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Stoneground: incomplete script1974 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Stoneground: Moore, Margaret (Ekue), 1974 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Stoneground production meeting records1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Stoneground production memos / Things for Cecile to Do1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Stoneground rehearsal log and notes [1 of 3]1974 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Stoneground rehearsal log and notes [2 of 3]1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Stoneground rehearsal log and notes [3 of 3]1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Stoneground script1974 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Stoneground: staging notes, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Trial: 1st draft1975 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Trial: 2nd draft1975 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Trial casting1975 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Trial: costumes, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Trial: costumes, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Trial performance notes1975 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Trial: production meetings, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Trial: publicity, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Trial: rehearsal log, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Trial: research, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Trial: Version A1975 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Trial: writing notes, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Trial rehearsal log and notes [1 of 4]1975 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Trial rehearsal log and notes [2 of 4]1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Trial rehearsal log and notes [3 of 4]1975 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Trial rehearsal log and notes [4 of 4]1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 5. Original developmental projects
    - Eats! (Bicentennial Donner Crossing piece) notes1976, Creator's Id No. 3.18 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Eats! (Bicentennial Donner Crossing piece) notes on text, Creator's Id No. 3.19 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Gilgamesh: preliminary scenario chart, Creator's Id No. 3.2 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Indian legends, Creator's Id No. 3.21 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous texts 1, Creator's Id No. 3.22 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous texts 2: Paltenghi Youth Center, San Francisco State University, Creator's Id No. 3.23 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous texts 3: Slave ship, group-developed text, Creator's Id No. 3.24 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous texts 4: Sinyavsky & Daniel, Creator's Id No. 3.25 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Philoctetes notes, Creator's Id No. 3.26 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Rat story, Creator's Id No. 3.27 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Scenarios: children, Creator's Id No. 3.28 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 6. Company documentation
    - BITEF Festival1974, Creator's Id No. 3.29 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Demeter Project, Creator's Id No. 3.3 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Film, Creator's Id No. 3.31 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Long Green Theater Company, Creator's Id No. 3.32 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Other companies, Creator's Id No. 3.33 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Other critics, Creator's Id No. 3.34 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Pasoli: Open Theater, Creator's Id No. 3.35 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Performance documentation, Creator's Id No. 3.37 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Programs [1 of 3]1940 - [199-], Creator's Id No. 3.38 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Programs [2 of 3]1940 - [199-], Creator's Id No. 3.38 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Programs [3 of 3]1940 - [199-], Creator's Id No. 3.38 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Clippings - other theater companies [1 of 2] (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Clippings - other theater companies [2 of 2] (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - N.Y. 1982: press, programs, Creator's Id No. 3.39 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - N.Y. 1982: Festival programs, Creator's Id No. 3.4 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - ProVisional Theater: Xa material, Creator's Id No. 3.41 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Roth: Bay Area avant garde1960 - 1971, Creator's Id No. 3.42 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - S.F. Mime Troup, Creator's Id No. 3.43 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Theatre of Man documentation / by Cecile Pineda, Creator's Id No. 3.44 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Theatre of Man: Experiments in the Underground, Creator's Id No. 3.45 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Series 2. Manuscripts
  - Subseries 1. Face
    - FACE: research, including original news article and analysis of Woman in the Dune for rhythm / suspense, Creator's Id No. 4.01 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - FACE: research: Stegman et al.: Basic dermatological surgery, Creator's Id No. 4.02 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - FACE: composition "blank" book, Creator's Id No. 4.03 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Contains composition of first part of FACE; journal and dream entries; as well as an unpublished account of an 1981 trip to Mexico esp., Chiapas and some locations (Zitacuaro) providing backgrounds for subsequent episodes of FACE.
    - FACE: Draft I, part 1, Creator's Id No. 4.04 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - FACE: Draft II, parts 1 & 2, Creator's Id No. 4.05 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - FACE: Draft III, Creator's Id No. 4.06 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - FACE: Draft IV, Creator's Id No. 4.07 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - FACE: Orchard chapter, Drafts I, II, & III, Creator's Id No. 4.08 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - FACE: rough draft IV from which final was typed, Creator's Id No. 4.09 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - FACE: re-writes, Creator's Id No. 4.1 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - FACE: rejected material (point of view shift), Creator's Id No. 4.11 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - FACE: penultimate draft, Creator's Id No. 4.12 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - FACE: draft typed by Poole for submission to Viking Penguin1982 July, Creator's Id No. 4.13 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - FACE: final draft: corrections, Creator's Id No. 4.14 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - FACE: final mss draft with author's corrections [1 of 3], Creator's Id No. 4.15 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - FACE: final mss draft with author's corrections [2 of 3], Creator's Id No. 4.15 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - FACE: final mss draft with author's corrections [3 of 3], Creator's Id No. 4.15 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - FACE: corrected proof [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 4.16 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - FACE: corrected proof [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 4.16 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - FACE: unpublished proof, Creator's Id No. 4.17 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - FACE: author's changes for FACE, filed with Viking-Penguin1985 Oct. 1, Creator's Id No. 4.18 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - FACE: Viking-Penguin contracts, Creator's Id No. 4.19 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - FACE: readers' comments, agent's comments, Creator's Id No. 4.2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - FACE: readers' comments, Squaw Valley Community of Writers [1 of 2], 1981, Creator's Id No. 4.21 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - FACE: readers' comments, Squaw Valley Community of Writers [2 of 2], 1981, Creator's Id No. 4.21 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - FACE: reviews, critical commentary, Creator's Id No. 4.22 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - FACE: first edition, hard cover, signed by the author, Creator's Id No. 4.23 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - FACE: excerpts anthologized in Daughters of the Fifth Sun, correspondence; corrected copy, Creator's Id No. 4.25 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - FACE: second edition, soft cover, signed by the author, Creator's Id No. 4.24 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Daughters of the Fifth Sun: uncorrected proof, Creator's Id No. 4.26 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - FACE: contracts: Life on the Water (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - FACE: filmscript, draft 1 [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 7.1 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - FACE: filmscript, draft 1 [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 7.1 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - FACE: filmscript, draft II, Creator's Id No. 7.2 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - FACE: screen adaptation / by Fields, Creator's Id No. 7.3 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - FACE: Deal memo - Northwood, Creator's Id No. 7.4 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - FACE: film research, etc., Creator's Id No. 7.5 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - FACE: filmscript: critical commentary, Creator's Id No. 7.6 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - FACE: Day Nye correspondence, Creator's Id No. 7.7 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - FACE: stage production, Creator's Id No. 7.8 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - FACE: film draft 2 with corrections, Creator's Id No. 7.9 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2. Frieze
    - FRIEZE research, Creator's Id No. 6.01 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - FRIEZE rough draft I, Creator's Id No. 6.02 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - FRIEZE, Part III, panels 33-48, Creator's Id No. 6.03 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - FRIEZE draft II [1 of 2],1984 Mar. - June, Creator's Id No. 6.04 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - FRIEZE draft II [2 of 2],1984 Mar. - June, Creator's Id No. 6.04 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - FRIEZE rough draft III, Creator's Id No. 6.05 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - FRIEZE draft III [1 of 3], 1985 Jan., Creator's Id No. 6.06 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - FRIEZE draft III [2 of 3], 1985 Jan., Creator's Id No. 6.06 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - FRIEZE draft III [3 of 3], 1985 Jan., Creator's Id No. 6.06 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - FRIEZE: corrections on draft IV from draft III1985 Feb. 28, Creator's Id No. 6.07 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - FRIEZE: penultimate draft, Creator's Id No. 6.08 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - FRIEZE: final mss, copyedited [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 6.09 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - FRIEZE: final mss, copyedited [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 6.09 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - FRIEZE: galley [1 of 3], 1986 Apr. 11, Creator's Id No. 6.1 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - FRIEZE: galley [2 of 3], 1986 Apr. 11, Creator's Id No. 6.1 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - FRIEZE: galley [3 of 3], 1986 Apr. 11, Creator's Id No. 6.1 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - FRIEZE: changes1986 Jan. - Apr., Creator's Id No. 6.11 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - FRIEZE: changes, Penguin (second) edition1987 Nov. 16, Creator's Id No. 6.12 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - FRIEZE: jacket copy, Creator's Id No. 6.13 (Box 24, Folder 9)